HIDANER FERRER - San Francisco, CA

(510) 340-8336 | hidanerferrer@gmail.com | www.HidanerFerrer.com | GitHub | English – Spanish

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Results-oriented and self-motivated Software Developer with a bachelor's in Electronic Engineering and professional experience developing Full-Stack applications including websites, data analytics/data visualization dashboards, and several independent projects that include iOS development. I have most recently engaged in workplace management to round out my skillset while allowing flexibility to complete a Computer Programming Certification at CCSF. There I have gained skills in Java, SQL and NoSQL Databases, Data Structures, JSON, XML, and Unix/Linux Operating Systems. In addition to the above, I have experience leading project management and business administration.

SOFTWARE SKILLS

JavaScript | Java | jQuery | HTML | CSS | Node.js | iOS | MySQL | MongoDB | React.js | AJAX | REST API | GitHub | Bootstrap Ruby on Rails | Responsive web design

WORK EXPERIENCE

Workplace Experience Coordinator | MICROSOFT – San Francisco, CA | April 2019 – Present

- Coordination and setup of mixed reality (MR) workshops and HoloLens demonstrations.
- Identification and resolution of problems related to information technology, equipment, and other office needs.
- Organization of and support for tech related events including Hackathons, Bootcamps, Tech Talks, and Tech related Meetups.

Software Developer | ENARA HEALTH – San Mateo, CA | Mar 2018 – Oct 2018

- Implementation lead for full-stack Lab Results Database with web-tool input platform for laboratory records.
- Developed front-end interface for Weight Dashboard and Lab Results Tracker for patients to see their progress while engaged on a weight loss program.
- Developed Clinical Dashboard to assist Primary Care Providers and Dietitians track patient progress by implementing a multiple database integration through Mode Analytics.
- Reduced by 85% time spent over the phone with Healthcare Insurance Companies for patient eligibility by supporting the development of an automated eligibility system on Salesforce CRM.

Technologies Used: JavaScript | NodeJS | HTML | CSS | REST API integration | MySQL | PostgreSQL | Sales Force Apex | Ruby on Rails | Mode Analytics | Data Visualization

Projects: InBody Weight Dashboard | Patient Labs Dashboard

Web Developer J. VILLALOBOS CONSULTING – San Francisco, CA | Oct 2017 – Jun 2018

- Designed, implemented, and developed user friendly commercial websites.
- Planned and designed website mockup for web components and UX redesign for existing commercial company websites.
- Engaged directly with customers to assess and solicit feedback regarding website requirements.

Technologies Used: JavaScript | HTML, CSS | WordPress | Sketch.

Projects: BayCO | Anderson Commercial Flooring

EDUCATION

Computer Programming: Java ■ CITY COLLEGE OF SAN FRANCISCO ■ San Francisco, CA. (2019-Present)

Java Fundamentals | Data Structure & Algorithms Java | SQL and no-SQL Database | JSON, XML

Full-Stack Web Developer ■ GENERAL ASSEMBLY ■ San Francisco, CA (2017)

480 hours immersive Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp

BS Electronic Engineering • Maracaibo, Venezuela (2009)

• Four year degree with emphasis in Automation and Control Systems.